<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Wilbur</title>
 <link href="wilburc.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="wilburc.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2016-03-04T21:57:38-06:00</updated>
 <id>wilburc.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Wilbur Chen</name>
   <email>wilburchen1@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Calluna</title>
   <link href="wilburc.github.io/2016/02/24/calluna/"/>
   <updated>2016-02-24T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>wilburc.github.io/2016/02/24/calluna</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Choosing a typeface is the most vexing, infuriating, time-consuming, and pleasurable part. &lt;br /&gt; &lt;br /&gt;— Richard Hendel, &lt;em&gt;On Book Design&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Similarly, designing a personal site is both frustrating and satisfying — you &lt;em&gt;know&lt;/em&gt; what you want. Intimate familiarity with our own personality and style demand precision in how we choose to represent ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How did I get to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.myfonts.com/person/Jos_Buivenga/&quot;&gt;Jos Buivenga&lt;/a&gt;’s Calluna?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;personality&quot;&gt;Personality&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As an amateur typographer (which is a &lt;em&gt;very&lt;/em&gt; generous title), I wanted to select a typeface that I felt represented me well, and conveyed my personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What resonated with me the most about Calluna is how, despite maintaining the appearance of a standard humanist serif, certain aspects of it have been modified to give it a subtle, unique feel. I find it important to embrace change and difference, while still remaining grounded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I grew up partially in Japan. My greatest takeaway was undoubtedly the unique Japanese culture — a dichotomy of tradition and progress. While seemingly incompatible, this unyielding connection to ancient culture complements their achievements in technological innovation. In design, I maintain deep respect and recognition for tried-and-tested usability principles and patterns. In fact, progress is born not from neglect of these principles, but from understanding of them. By understanding the origins and contexts of these principles, we can learn to adapt or build off of them, creating value and exploring new ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/2_24_calluna_1.png&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calluna’s asymmetrical characters create a unique and fresh new feel, for an otherwise traditional humanist serif. Despite being gently rooted in old-style aesthetic, several aspects of the characters, such as the serifs and the shoulders, slope towards the upper-right corner, creating a forward flow. These details give it a crisp perkiness uncommon in old-style typefaces, while maintaining the formality, credibility, and robustness.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;style&quot;&gt;Style&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having written much of the content before the design process, I knew there was an abundance of italics throughout the writing — in an attempt to capture the many stresses and intonations I use colloquially. The italic style of Calluna is elegant and fluid, but more importantly, maintains the confidence and density of the regular characters. While other italics often crumple under the stature of their normal-weighted neighbors, Calluna’s proudly stand among them, fitting in, while still occasionally flaunting their magnificence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/2_24_calluna_2.png&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apart from the &lt;em&gt;em dash&lt;/em&gt;, my most commonly used form of punctuation is probably the question mark — often closing rhetorical questions in my writing. Calluna’s question marks are less formal and decorated than those of other fonts — the sleek curvature helps the sentence main its flow and direction. Instead of ending the sentence with a flourish and waiting for a response, Calluna’s uncomplicated question marks preserve the flow of the sentence, making for a frank and slightly sassy transition into the next thought.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;thats-it&quot;&gt;That’s it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, I went through dozens of typefaces, looking for the perfect body font, landing on regular 20-point Calluna. It was selected for its synthesis of traditional humanist features, along with unique asymmetry and flow. Whether it accurately represents me is up for contention, as most areas of subjectivity are. I can’t convince you that Calluna is a typographic representation of me in my purest form, but I &lt;em&gt;can&lt;/em&gt; explain my process and thinking, and let you decide for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Humbly,&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>We’re back!</title>
   <link href="wilburc.github.io/2016/02/23/new-site/"/>
   <updated>2016-02-23T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>wilburc.github.io/2016/02/23/new-site</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the past 12 months, I’ve probably created at least 30 versions of my personal portfolio site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Wow, what a perfectionist!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Maaaybe&lt;/em&gt;. But the truth is, I really just had no idea what I was doing.*&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;80-20. Or rather, 20-80.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;*Not that I’m some sort of front-end genius now&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;technologies&quot;&gt;Technologies&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to build sites out of nothing but pure, unadulterated HTML/CSS/JavaScript. Out of nothing but ignorance, maybe. You can probably imagine how messy &lt;em&gt;that&lt;/em&gt; got — it was like building a house out of wet cardboard and stripped yarn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One year of constant iteration and two sketchbooks later, I dedicated a weekend to nothing but brunch and this site, and today I humbly present the result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Built with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, graciously assisted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpoole.com/&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Image zooming made possible and easy with &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/fat/zoom.js/tree/master&quot;&gt;zoom.js&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.exljbris.com/&quot;&gt;Jos Buivenga&lt;/a&gt;’s beautiful Calluna and Calluna Sans served by &lt;a href=&quot;http://typekit.com&quot;&gt;Adobe Typekit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A more detailed write-up with images and stuff may or may not be in the works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good night,
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Literally the worst.</title>
   <link href="wilburc.github.io/2016/02/19/literally-the-worst/"/>
   <updated>2016-02-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>wilburc.github.io/2016/02/19/literally-the-worst</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Few things on the internet really annoy me—but those that do, make me want to cry over their designer’s keyboards so they can never violate a user’s sanity ever again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/2_19_post_password_pic.png&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-dont-want-to-think&quot;&gt;I don’t want to think.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Account registration should not require any thought.  As a way to a means, it’s meant to be quick and painless. It &lt;em&gt;has&lt;/em&gt; to be. &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/uie-brain-sparks/the-300-million-button-76b566ae5f73#.f9s0swo4i&quot;&gt;Several&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nngroup.com/articles/optional-registration/&quot;&gt;studies&lt;/a&gt; have shown that account registration is a wall that people aren’t willing to scale — unless they &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want whatever lies on the other side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;my-worst-online-experience&quot;&gt;My worst online experience&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, you may think that the password incident above was from an old, under-designed website. That may be true—but an incident equally egregious, an experience that claims the #1 spot in my “Worst digital experiences 1993–2016,” occurred at the hands of a company you’ve definitely heard of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/2_19_itunes_store.png&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a reason why I still hesitate to use iTunes for anything.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/2_19_reset_pw_1.png&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is all under the assumption that I don’t know the answer to my security questions. I’ll save this for another post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/2_19_reset_pw_2.png&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s very hard to switch your country preferences — especially if you don’t know your password.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/2_19_reset_pw_3.png&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My new password must be:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;At least 8 characters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Contain both uppercase/lowercase letters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have at least one number&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/2_19_reset_pw_4.png&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite fulfilling all of the criteria, there was a &lt;em&gt;hidden&lt;/em&gt; condition—that your password cannot be “too easy to guess.” I thought that was the whole point of the 3 criteria above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/files/2_19_reset_pw_5.png&quot; data-action=&quot;zoom&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m interested in seeing any studies that show that people generally use the same 2-3 passwords for all their accounts. I ended up using one of my fallback ones that miraculously &lt;em&gt;did&lt;/em&gt; satisfy the 4th &lt;em&gt;hidden&lt;/em&gt; requirement…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;…and obviously, because of that, it’s already been used before and can’t be used again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Signing off,
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Wilbur&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>NewYearNewMe</title>
   <link href="wilburc.github.io/2016/02/01/new-year-new-me/"/>
   <updated>2016-02-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>wilburc.github.io/2016/02/01/new-year-new-me</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This site is built with &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, on top of the  &lt;a href=&quot;http://github.com/poole/poole&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt; template.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details to come soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;i&gt;-Wilbur&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
